You now know a bunch about machine learning.
你现在已经掌握不少机器学习知识了
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
In this video, I like to
在这段视频中
teach you a programing language,
我将教你一种编程语言
Octave, in which you'll be
Octave语言
able to very quickly implement
你能够用它来非常迅速地
the the learning algorithms we've
实现这门课中我们已经学过
seen already, and the learning
或者将要学的
algorithms we'll see later in this course.
机器学习算法
In the past, I've tried to teach machine learning
过去我一直尝试用不同的编程语言
using a large variety of different programming languages
来教授机器学习
including C++ Java,
包括C++、Java、
Python, NumPy, and also
Python、Numpy
Octave, and what I
和 Octave
found was that students were able
我发现当使用像
to learn the most
Octave这样的
productively learn the most quickly
高级语言时
and prototype your algorithms most
学生能够更快
quickly using a relatively
更好地学习
high level language like octave.
并掌握这些算法
In fact, what I often
事实上 在硅谷
see in Silicon Valley is
我经常看到的情况是
that if even if you need to build.
进行大规模的
If you want to build a large
机器学习项目的人
scale deployment of a learning
通常会使用的
algorithm, what people will often do
程序语言
is prototype and the language is Octave.
就是Octave
Which is a great prototyping language.
Octave是一种很好的原始语言(prototyping language)
So you can sort of get your learning algorithms working quickly.
使用Octave 你能快速地实现你的算法
And then only if you need
剩下的事情 你只需要
to a very large scale deployment of it.
进行大规模的资源配置
Only then spend your time
你只用再花时间
re-implementing the algorithm
用C++或Java这些语言
to C++ Java or some of the language like that.
把算法重新实现就行了
Because all the lessons we've learned is
因为我们知道
that a time or develop a time.
开发项目的时间
That is your time.
或者说你的时间 是很宝贵的
The machine learning's time is incredibly valuable.
机器学习的时间也是很宝贵的
And if you can
所以 如果你能
get your learning algorithms to work more quickly in Octave.
让你的学习算法在Octave上快速的实现
Then overall you have a
基本的想法实现以后
huge time savings by first
再用C++或者Java去改写
developing the algorithms in
这样
Octave, and then implementing and
你就能节省出
maybe C++ Java, only after we have the ideas working.
大量的时间
The most common prototyping language I
据我所见 人们使用最多的
see people use for machine
用于机器学习的原始语言
learning are: Octave, MATLAB,
是Octave、MATLAB
Python, NumPy, and R.
Python、NumPy 和 R
Octave is nice because open sourced.
Octave很好 因为它是开源的
And MATLAB works well
当然 MATLAB也很好
too, but it is expensive for
但它不是每个人都
to many people.
买得起的
But if you have access to a copy of MATLAB.
但是 如果你能够使用MATLAB
You can also use MATLAB with this class.
你也可以在这门课里面使用
If you know Python, NumPy,
如果你会Python、NumPy
or if you know R. I do see some people use it.
或者R语言 我也见过有人用 R 的
But, what I see is
但是 据我所知
that people usually end up
这些人不得不中途放弃了
developing somewhat more slowly, and
因为这些语言在开发上比较慢
you know, these languages.
而且 因为这些语言
Because the Python, NumPy syntax
Python、NumPy的语法
is just slightly clunkier than the Octave syntax.
相较于Octave来说 还是更麻烦一点
And so because of that, and
正因为这样
because we are releasing starter
也因为我们最开始
code in Octave.
用Octave来写程序
I strongly recommend that you
所以我强烈建议你
not try to do the following exercises in this class in NumPy and R.
不要用NumPy或者R来完整这门课的作业
But that I do recommend that
我建议你
you instead do the programming exercises
在这门课中
for this class in octave instead.
用Octave来写程序
What I'm going to do in
接下来
this video is go through
本视频将快速地介绍
a list of commands very,
一系列的命令
very quickly, and its goal
目标是迅速地展示
is to quickly show you the
通过这一系列Octave的命令
range of commands and the range of things you can do in Octave.
让你知道Octave能用来做什么
The course website will have
我们的网站会提供
a transcript of everything I
所有我在视频中提到的
do, and so after
内容的文本
watching this video you
所以 当你看完这个视频
can refer to the transcript
想查询一些命令时
posted on the course website
你可以查看这些资料
when you want find a command.
这些都放在网上了
Concretely, what I recommend
总之 我建议你
you do is first watch the tutorial videos.
先看教学视频
And after watching to the
之后
end, then install Octave on your computer.
把Octave安装到电脑上
And finally, it goes to
最后 去这门课的网站上
the course website, download the transcripts
下载这门课的
of the things you see in the
相关文档和视频
session, and type in
然后 你可以试着
whatever commands seem interesting
在Octave中键入一些
to you into Octave, so that it's
有趣的命令
running on your own computer, so
让程序运行在你的电脑上
you can see it run for yourself.
这样你可以看到程序是怎么运行的
And with that let's get started.
让我们开始吧
Here's my Windows desktop, and I'm going to start up Octave.
这里是我的Windows桌面 启动Octave
And I'm now in Octave.
现在打开Octave
And that's my Octave prompt.
这是Octave命令行
Let me first show the elementary
现在让我示范
operations you can do in Octave.
最基本的Octave代码
So you type in 5 + 6.
输入5 + 6
That gives you the answer of 11.
然后得到11
3 - 2.
输入3 - 2
5 x 8, 1/2, 2^6
5×8、1/2、2 ^ 6
is 64.
得到64
So those are the elementary math operations.
这些都是基本的数学运算
You can also do logical operations.
你也可以做逻辑运算
So one equals two.
例如 1==2
This evaluates to false.
计算结果为 false  ( 假 )
The percent command here means a comment.
这里的百分号命令表示注释
So, one equals two, evaluates to false.
1==2 计算结果为假
Which is represents by zero.
这里用0表示
One not equals to two.
1 ~= 2
This is true.
这是真的
So that returns one.
因此返回1
Note that a not equal sign
请注意 不等于符号的写法
is this tilde equals symbol.
是这个波浪线加上等于符号 ( ~= )
And not bang equals.
而不是等于感叹号加等号 ( != )
Which is what some other
这是和其他一些
programming languages use.
编程语言中不太一样的地方
Lets see logical operations one and zero
让我们看看逻辑运算 1 && 0
use a double ampersand sign to
使用双＆符号
the logical AND.
表示逻辑与
And that evaluates false.
1 && 0判断为假
One or zero is the OR operation.
1和0的或运算 1 || 0
And that evaluates to true.
其计算结果为真
And I can XOR one and
还有异或运算 如XOR ( 1, 0 )
zero, and that evaluates to one.
其返回值为1
This thing over on the left, this Octave 324.x
从左向右写着 Octave 324.x版本
equals 11, this is the default Octave prompt.
其计算结果等于11 这是默认的Octave提示
It shows the, what, the
它显示了当前Octave的版本
version in Octave and so on.
以及相关的其它信息
If you don't want that prompt,
如果你不想看到那个提示
there's a somewhat cryptic command PF
这里有一个隐藏的命令
quote, greater than, greater
输入命令
than and so on,
PS('>>  ');
that you can use to change the prompt.
现在你看到的就是等待命令的快捷提示
And I guess this quote a string in the middle.
这句话在中间有一个字符串
Your quote, greater than, greater than, space.
('>>  ');
That's what I prefer my Octave prompt to look like.
这是我喜欢的命令行样子
So if I hit enter.
这里敲一个回车
Oops, excuse me.
抱歉 写错了
Like so.
这样才对
PS1 like so.
要写成PS1这样
Now my Octave prompt has changed to the greater than, greater than sign.Which,
现在命令提示已经变得简化了
you know, looks quite a bit better.
这样看起来很棒
Next let's talk about Octave variables.
接下来 我们将谈到Octave的变量
I can take the variable
现在写一个变量
A and assign it to 3.
对变量A赋值为3
And hit enter.
并按下回车键
And now A is equal to 3.
显示变量A等于3
You want to assign a variable, but you don't want to print out the result.
如果你想分配一个变量 但不希望在屏幕上显示结果
If you put a semicolon, the semicolon
你可以在命令后加一个分号
suppresses the print output.
可以抑制打印输出
So to do that, enter, it doesn't print anything.
敲入回车后 不打印任何东西。
Whereas A equals 3.
A等于3
mix it, print it out,
只是不显示出来
where A equals, 3 semicolon doesn't print anything.
其中这句命令不打印任何东西
I can do string assignment.
现在举一个字符串的例子
B equals hi
变量b等于"hi"
Now if I just
现在
enter B it prints out the
如果我输入b
variable B. So B is the string hi
则会显示字符串变量b的值"hi"
C equals 3 greater than colon 1.
C等于3大于等于1
So, now C evaluates the true.
所以 现在C变量的值是真
If you want to print
如果你想打印出变量
out or display a variable, here's how you go about it.
或显示一个变量 你可以像下面这么做
Let me set A equals Pi.
设置A等于圆周率π
And if I want to print
如果我要打印该值
A I can just type A like so, and it will print it out.
那么只需键入A 像这样 就打印出来了
For more complex printing there is
对于更复杂的屏幕输出
also the DISP command which stands for Display.
也可以用DISP命令显示
Display A just prints out A like so.
Disp( A )就相当于像这样打印出A
You can also display strings
你也可以用该命令来显示字符串
so: DISP, sprintf, two
输入disp sprintf
decimals, percent 0.2,
小数 0.2%
F, comma, A. Like so.
逗号 A 像这样
And this will print out the string.
通过这条命令将打印出字符串
Two decimals, colon, 3.14.
打印显示为“两位小数：3.14”
This is kind of
这是一种
an old style C syntax.
旧风格的C语言语法
For those of you that
对于之前
have programmed C before, this is
就学过C语言的同学来说
essentially the syntax you use to print screen.
你可以使用这种基本的语法来将结果打印到屏幕
So the Sprintf generates a
Sprintf命令生成一个字符串
string that is less
不仅仅是
than the 2 decimals, 3.1 plus string.
字符串“2 decimal：3.14”
This percent 0.2 F means
其中的“0.2％F”表示
substitute A into here,
代替A放在这里
showing the two digits after the decimal points.
并显示A值的小数点后两位数字
And DISP takes the string
同时DISP 命令对字符串做出操作
DISP generates it by the Sprintf command.
DISP命令输出
Sprintf.
Sprintf产生的字符串
The Sprintf command.
Sprintf命令
And DISP actually displays the string.
和DISP命令显示字符串
And to show you another
再说一个细节
example, Sprintf six decimals
例如 sprintf命令的六个小数
percent 0.6 F comma A.
0.6％F ,A
And, this should print Pi
这应该打印π
with six decimal places.
的6位小数形式
Finally, I was saying, a like so, looks like this. There
最后 看起来像这样
are useful shortcuts that type type formats long.
也有一些控制输出长短格式的快捷命令
It causes strings by default.
默认情况下 是字符串
Be displayed to a lot more decimal places.
显示出的小数位有点多
And format short is a
短 ( short ) 格式
command that restores the default
是默认的输出格式
of just printing a small number of digits.
只是打印小数数位的第一位
Okay, that's how you work with variables.
相关这方面的内容还需要你继续练习
Now let's look at vectors and matrices.
下面 让我们来看看向量和矩阵
Let's say I want to assign MAT A to the matrix.
比方说 建立一个矩阵A
Let me show you an example: 1, 2,
输入1  2
semicolon, 3, 4, semicolon, 5, 6.
; 3 4  ;  5 6
This generates a three by
这会产生一个
two matrix A whose first
三行两列的矩阵A
row is 1, 2. Second row
其第一行是1 2
3, 4. Third row is 5, 6.
第二行是3 4 第三行是5 6
What the semicolon does is
分号的作用
essentially say, go to
从本质上来说
the next row of the matrix.
就是在矩阵内换行到下一行
There are other ways to type this in.
此外 还有其他的方法来建立矩阵A
Type A 1, 2 semicolon
输入A矩阵的值 1 2 分号
3, 4, semicolon, 5, 6, like so.
3 4 分号 5 6
And that's another equivalent way of
这是另一种方法
assigning A to be
对A矩阵进行赋值
the values of this three by two matrix.
考虑到这是一个三行两列的矩阵
Similarly you can assign vectors.
你同样可以用向量
So V equals 1, 2, 3.
建立向量V并赋值1 2 3
This is actually a row vector.
V是一个行向量
Or this is a 3 by 1 vector.
或者说是一个3 ( 列 )×1 ( 行 ) 的向量
Where that is a fat Y vector,
一个胖胖的Y向量
excuse me, not, this is
或者说
a 1 by 3 matrix, right.
一行三列的矩阵
Not 3   by 1.
注意不是三行一列
If I want to assign
如果我想
this to a column vector,
分配一个列向量
what I would do instead is do v 1;2;3.
我可以写“1;2;3”
And this will give me a 3 by 1.
现在便有了一个
There's a 1 by 3 vector.
3 行 1 列 的向量
So this will be a column vector.
同时这是一个列向量
Here's some more useful notation.
下面是一些更为有用的符号
V equals 1: 0.1: 2.
V等于1：0.1：2
What this does is
这个该如何理解呢
it sets V to the bunch
这个集合V是一组值
of elements that start from 1.
从数值1开始
And increments and steps
增量或说是步长为0.1
of 0.1 until you get up to 2.
直到增加到2
So if I do this, V is going to be this, you know, row vector.
按照这样的方法对向量V操作 可以得到一个行向量
This is what one by eleven matrix really.
这是一个1行11列的矩阵
That's 1, 1.1, 1.2, 1.3 and
其矩阵的元素是1  1.1  1.2  1.3
so on until we
依此类推
get up to two.
直到数值2
Now, and I can also
现在 我也可以
set V equals one colon six,
建立一个集合V并用命令“1:6”进行赋值
and that sets V to be these numbers.
这样V就被赋值了
1 through 6, okay.
1至6的六个整数
Now here are some other ways to generate matrices.
这里还有一些其他的方法来生成矩阵
Ones 2.3 is a command
例如“ones(2, 3)”
that generates a matrix that
也可以用来生成矩阵
is a two by three matrix
其结果为一个两行三列的矩阵
that is the matrix of all ones.
不过矩阵中的所有元素都为1
So if I set that c2
当我想生成一个
times ones two by
元素都为2
three this generates a
两行三列的矩阵
two by three matrix that is all two's.
就可以使用这个命令
You can think of this as a
你可以把这个方法当成一个
shorter way of writing this and
生成矩阵的快速方法
c2,2,2's and you can
当你想生成一个三维2×2×2的矩阵时
call them 2,2,2, which would also give you the same result.
你就可以用这个“ones”命令
Let's say W equals one's, one
比方说
by three, so this is
w是一个有三个1的
going to be a row vector
行向量
or a row of
或者说一行
three one's and similarly
由三个同样的1组成的向量
you can also say w equals
你也可以说
zeroes, one by
w为一个
three, and this generates a matrix.
一行三列的零矩阵
A one by three matrix of all zeros.
一行三列的A矩阵里的元素全部是零
Just a couple more ways to generate matrices .
还有很多的方式来生成矩阵
If I do W equals
如果我对W进行赋值
Rand one by three,
用Rand命令建立一个一行三列的矩阵
this gives me a one
因为使用了Rand命令
by three matrix of all random numbers.
则其一行三列的元素均为随机值
If I do Rand
如果我使用
three by three.
“rand(3, 3)”命令
This gives me a three by
这就生成了一个
three matrix of all
3×3的矩阵
random numbers drawn from the
并且其所有元素均为随机
uniform distribution between zero and one.
数值介于0和1之间
So every time I do
所以
this, I get a different
正是因为这一点
set of random numbers drawn
我们可以得到
uniformly between zero and one.
数值均匀介于0和1之间的元素
For those of you that
如果
know what a Gaussian random variable
你知道什么是高斯随机变量
is or for those of you that
或者
know what a normal random variable
你知道什么是正态分布的随机变量
is, you can also set W
你可以设置集合W
equals Rand N, one by three.
使其等于一个一行三列的N矩阵
And so these are going
并且
to be three values drawn from
来自三个值
a Gaussian distribution with mean
一个平均值为0的高斯分布
zero and variance or
方差
standard deviation equal to one.
或者等于1的标准偏差
And you can set more complex
还可以设置地更复杂
things like W equals minus
例如
six, plus the square root
W减去6 再加上10的平方
ten, times, lets say
两者相乘
Rand N, one by ten thousand.
Rand命令生成一个1行10000列的矩阵
And I'm going to put a semicolon at
把分号放到末尾
the end because I don't really want this printed out.
这样结果就打印不出来
This is going to be a what?
那这样会得到什么呢
Well, it's going to
这样就可以
be a vector of, with
得到
a hundred thousand, excuse me, ten thousand elements.
一个有10000元素的向量
So, well, actually, you know what?
想知道具体是多少
Let's print it out.
我们也可把它打印出来
So this will generate a matrix like this.
这将产生一个这样的矩阵
Right?
看
With 10,000 elements.
这就是一个
So that's what W is.
有着10000个元素的矩阵W
And if I now
如果我现在
plot a histogram of W
用绘制直方图命令
with a hist command, I can
绘制出一个直方图
now. And Octave's print hist
使用Octave的
command, you know, takes a
打印直方图命令
couple seconds to bring this up,
你只需要数秒钟就可以将它绘制出来
but this is a histogram of
这是一个对随机变量W
my random variable for W.
绘制出的直方图
There was minus 6 plus zero
这里是-6+0
ten times this Gaussian random variable.
乘上十倍的高斯随机变量
And I can plot a histogram with
这样 可以绘制出一个
more buckets, with more bins, with say, 50 bins.
有着更多条的 乃至50个条的直方图来
And this is my
这样 就有一个
histogram of a Gaussian with mean minus 6.
均值减去6的高斯直方图
Because I have a minus
因为这里是
6 there plus square root 10 times this.
-6加10的平方根并与这项相乘
So the variance of
因此
this Gaussian random variable
这个高斯随机变量的方差
is 10 on the standard deviation is
是10
square root of 10, which is about what?
且其标准偏差为10的平方根
Three point one.
3.1
Finally, one special command
最后 说一个生成矩阵的
for generator matrix, which is the I command.
特殊命令I
So I stands for this
其实
is maybe a pun on the word identity.
I也可说是一个双关语字标识
It's server set eye 4.
设置一个4阶单位矩阵
This is the 4 by 4 identity matrix.
这是一个4×4矩阵
So I equals eye 4.
所以I为“eye(4)”
This gives me a 4 by 4 identity matrix.
通过上面的命令得到4×4矩阵
And I equals eye 5,  eye 6.
I可以等于5阶单位阵 6阶单位阵
That gives me a 6 by
那么就有
6 identity matrix, i3
6阶单位阵
is the 3 by 3 identity matrix.
eye( 3 )是一个3阶方阵
Lastly, to
在本节视频的最后
wrap up this video, there's one more useful command.
还有一个比较有用的命令
Which is the help command.
那就是帮助命令
So you can type help i and
例如 你可以键入help i
this brings up the help function for the identity matrix.
它就会将矩阵的相关信息显示出来
Hit Q to quit.
命令Q可以退出Octave
And you can also type help rand.
你也可以键入help rand
Brings up documentation for the rand or the
将会显示出有关rand函数的相关帮助文档
random number generation function.
以及相关的随机数生成函数
Or even help help, which
甚至可以使用命令help help
shows you, you know help on the help function.
将会显示出help命令的使用方法
So, those are the
以上讲解的内容
basic operations in Octave.
都是Octave的基本操作
And with this you should be
希望你能通过上面的讲解
able to generate a few matrices, multiply, add things.
自己练习一些矩阵、乘、加等操作
And use the basic operations in Octave.
将这些操作在Octave中熟练
In the next video, I'd like
在接下来的视频中
to start talking about more
将会涉及
sophisticated commands and how
更多复杂的命令
to use data around and start to process data in Octave.
并使用它们在Octave中对数据进行更多的操作